Guide to the Thomas Andrew Bailey Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Thomas Andrew Bailey papers
1927-1981
SC0054
Bailey, Thomas Andrew, 1902-1983.
53.5 Linear feet
Correspondence, primarily with colleagues and also with policical figures, editors and publishers, personal friends, and various Stanford University agencies, committees, and departments. Includes manuscript materials used in publications, bibiliographical and biographical materials, and some personal records.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Thomas Bailey and others, 1968-1978, and the Bailey estate, 1983.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of history at Stanford University (1931-1968; emeritus 1968-1983), Thomas Bailey received his A.B. (1924), A.M. (1925), and Ph.D. (1927) in History from Stanford. A prolific writer in American history, his work includes several history text-books. He died in 1983.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, primarily with colleagues and also with policical figures, editors and publishers, personal friends, and various Stanford University agencies, committees, and departments. Includes manuscript materials used in publications, bibiliographical and biographical materials, and some personal records.
Access Terms
Bailey, Thomas Andrew, 1902-1983.; Bemis, Samuel Flagg, 1891-1973.; Cottrell, Edwin Angell, 1881-; Curti, Merle (Merle Eugene), 1897-1996; De Conde, Alexander.; Earle, Edward Mead, 1894-1954.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Lutz, Ralph Haswell, 1886-1968.; McAdoo, William Gibbs.; Nevins, Allan, 1890-1971.; Robinson, Edgar Eugene, 1887-1977; Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, 1917-; Stanford University. Department of History. Students.; Wish, Harvey, 1909-; Historical research.; Lectures.; Manuscripts (for publication).; Notes.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1927-1967; Series 1
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Crawford, D. L. - President, University of Hawaii, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Leebrick,K.C. - Professor of History, University of Hawaii, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - McKay, Donald C., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Crawford, D. L. - President,University of Hawaii, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Leebrick, K. C. - Dean, College of Liberal Arts, Syracuse University, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Martin, P. A. - Professor of History, Stanford University, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Robinson, E. E. - Professor of History, Stanford University, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Wilson, Francis G. - Department of Political Science, University of Wisconsin, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Crawford, D. L., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Clyde, Paul H. - Department of History, Ohio State University, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Chase, Mary Katherine, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - George, William H. - Department of Political Science, University of Washington, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Leebrick, K. C., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lutz, Ralph H. - Director, Hoover War Library, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Wilson, Francis G., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Creer, L. H. - Department of History, University of Washington, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - George, W. H. - Dean, College of Arts and Sciences, University of Hawaii, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hulme, E. M. - Department of History, Stanford University, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Leebrick, K. C., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Martin, C. E. - Department of Political Science, University of Washington, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Swain, Robert E. - acting President, Stanford University; appointment as acting assistant professor of History, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bolton, H. E. - Department of History, UC Berkeley, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Crawford, D. L., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cottrell, E. A. - Chairman, Council of Research in Social Sciences, Stanford, re grants for summer research work in Washington, DC, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Erwin, E. S. - Comptroller, Stanford, for purchasing house, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - George, W. H., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Johnson, Hiram W. - United States Senator, California, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Leebrick, K. C., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Martin, C. E., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Parish, John C. - UCLA, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Swain, Robert E., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bourne, Henry E. - American Historical Review, re publishing articles, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bolton, Herbert E., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Crawford, D. L., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cottrell, E. A., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - George, William H., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Koontz, Louis Knott - Pacific Historical Review, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Leebrick, K. C., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Martin, Royal C., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Martin, C. E., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Parish, John C., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Swain, R. E. - about research expenditures, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jaggart, Harold J., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Albright, R. E. - Department of History, University of Montana, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bourne, H. E., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Crawford, D. L., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Farley, Miriam S. - Political Science Quarterly, about publication of some articles, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Johnson, Hiram W. - United States Senator, California, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Leebrick, K. C., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Koontz, Louis K., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - McAdoo, W. G. - United States Senator, California, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Parrish, J. C., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman - research funds, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, A-F, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Albright, R. E., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bourne, H. E. - about publication of articles, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bolton, H. E., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Cottrell, E. A. - about research funds, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Davies, W. H. - Stanford University Press, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, F-M, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Friend, N. A. - Stanford University Press manager, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Gabriel, R. H. - Department of History, Yale University, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Jameson, J. F. -Division of Manuscript, Library of Congress, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - von Klenze, Camillo - about renting out of house, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lutz, R. H. - Dean, Graduate Study, Stanford University, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - McAdoo, William G. - United States Senator, California, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Meyer, J. - Committee on National Archives Survey, Library of Congress, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Marten, Royal C., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, P-Z, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Parish, J. C., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Sprinks, Nelson - Reconstruction Finance Corporation, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Spindler, Arno - Admiral, German Navy, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Jensky, William W. - Arizona State Teacher's College, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman - President, Stanford, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, A-C, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Arbuckle, Ernest C., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bourne, H. E., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Baxter, James P. - Harvard University, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Briggs, Reid - Secretary to Senator W. G. McAdoo, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Cottrell, E. A., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, C-J, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Crofts, J. S. - publisher, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Chun, Kenneth - Lingnan University, Canton, China, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dean, Arthur L. - Mrs. Bailey's father, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Emerson, J. G., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Fox, Frank L., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, K-R, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Littler, Robert, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Leonard, E. B. - Oakland Chamber of Commerce, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - McDowell, J. E. - Academic Secretary, Stanford University, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Parish, J. C., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ragaty, L. J. - Department of History, George Washington University, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Reid, J. M. - Harcourt, Brace and Co., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, R-Z, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Spindler, Arno, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Savelle, Max - Department of History, Stanford University, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Spinks, C. N., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tinsley, William W., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Wilson, J. G., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Wilber, Allen S. - Vice President, J. S. Crofts and Co., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Weigel, Stanley A. - San Francisco lawyer, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, A-C, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Alfaro, Ricardo J. - Minister Plenitpotentiary of Panama, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Briggs, Reid, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bourne, H. E., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bolton, H. E., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bemis, Samuel T. - Yale University, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, C-H, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Crawford, David, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Cottrell, E. A., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Ellison, J. W. - Department of History, Oregon State College, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - George, W. H., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Hunter, C. H. - Arizona State Teacher's College, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, H-R, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Leebrick, K. C., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Martin, P. A. - Department of History, University of Michigan, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Marvin, C. H. - President, George Washington University, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - O'Connor, E. A. - about payment of delinquent taxes in Hawaii, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Parish, J. C., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Ragatz, L. J., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, S-Z, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Savelle, Max, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Spindler, Arno, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Schmitt, B. E. - Editor, Journal of Modern History, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Tinsley, William W., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Van Alstyne, Richard U. - Chico State College, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, A-H, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - George, W. H., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Gray, Wood - Executive Head, Department of History, George Washingon University, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, H-N, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Hunter, C. H., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Hobbs, James - State Department, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Lutz, Ralph H., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Martin, C. E., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Mitchell, Thornton, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Marvin, C. H., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Oakie, John H. - American Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, P-Z, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Ragatz, L. J., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Von Alstyne, R., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Weigel, Stanley A., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Wedel, Oswald, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, A-B, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Anderson, Charles D. -Macmillan Company, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bolton, H. E., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bemis, S. F., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Blue, George V. - State Department, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Brooks, Philip - National Archives, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Briggs, Reid, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, B-D, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Crofts, F. S., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Case, Lynn M. - Louisiana State University, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Caughey, John W. - History Department, UCLA, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Fisher, H. H., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Ellison, J. W., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Ettinger, Amos A. - Department of History, Lehigh University, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, F-H, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Gage, Daniel J. - Bucknell University, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Griffin, Charles C. - Department of History, Vassar College, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Holt, U. Stull - Department of History, Johns Hopkins University, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Herrick, Francis - American Historical Association, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Hunter, C. H., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, H, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Hobbs, J. A. - State Department, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Howe, George F. - Department of History, Amherst College, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, H-M, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Lyon, E. Wilson - Department of History, Colgate University, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Koontz, Louis K., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Lanning, J. J. - Department of History, Duke University, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Keate, Edith M., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Lutz, Ralph, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Mitchell, Thornton, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, M-S, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Martin, Thomas P. - Division of Manuscripts, Library of Congress, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Notter, Harley - State Department, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Osborn, Clarence - San Diego State College, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Nevins, Allan - History Department, Columbia University, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Oakie, John H., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Ragatz, L. J., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Spindler, Arno, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, S-T, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Savage, Carlton - State Department, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Savelle, Max, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Tatum, Edward H. - Huntington Library, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Tansill, Charles C., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Tinsley, William W., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, V-Z, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Von Alstyne, R. W., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Wright, Gordon, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, A-B, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, John Z. - California Congressman, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Beardsley, Charles E. - Los Angeles attorney, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bolton, H. C., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bemis, S. F., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Birch, C. A. - of F. S. Crofts and Co., about publication of Bailey's Diplomatic History, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, B-C, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Birch, C. A., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Crofts, F. S., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, C, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Crofts, F. S., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Cottrell, E. A., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Caughey, John W. - Department of History, UCLA, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Cameron, Meribeth - History Department, Western Reserve University, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, C-F, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Fox, Dixon Ryan - President, Union College, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ellis, Elmer - Department of History, University of Missouri, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ferrar, Victor J. - State Department, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, F-H, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Earle, Edward M. - Institute for Advanced Studies, Princeton, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Gage, Daniel J. - Bucknell University, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Hicks, J. D. - Department of History, University of Wisconsin, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Herrick, F. H., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, H-K, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Holt, W. Stull - Department of History, Johns Hopkins University, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Hardy, Osgood - Occidential College, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Koontz, Louis K., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Kuykendall, Ralph - University of Hawaii, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, L-N, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Loomis, Francis B., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mitchell, Thornton, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Martin, Thomas P., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Muzzy, David S. - Department of History, Columbia University, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Notter, Harley, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, N-P, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Nevins, Allan, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Oakie, John H., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Perkins, Dexter - Department of History, University of Rochester, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, P-S, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ragatz, L. J., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Spindler, Arno, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Savage, Carlton - State Department, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Spinks, Charles N., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Sterling, J. C. Wallace, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, S-Z, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Savelle, Max, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Von Alstyne, R. W., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Tinsley, William, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Wilber, A. S. - F. C. Crofts and Co., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Wright, Gordon, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, A-C, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Blue, George V., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Beale, Howard K. - Department of History, University of North Carolina, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Crofts, F. S., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Caughey, John, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cottrell, E. A., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, D-J, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ellison, J. W., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Earle, Edward M., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gros, Robert R., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hunter, Charles P., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Holt, W. Stull, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, J-L, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Kuykendall, Ralph S. - Department of History, University of Hawaii, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Koontz, Louis K., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Lattimore, Owen - Johns Hopkins University, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, M-S, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Martin, C. E., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Mtichell, Thornton, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Martin, Thomas P., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Savelle, Max, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, S-T, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Spindler, Arno, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Spaulding, E. Wilder - State Department, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Tatum, Edward H., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, T-Z, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Van Alstyne, R. W., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Ward, Stuart R. - Executive Secretary, Commonwealth Club of California, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Wilber, Allen S., 1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, A-C, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bretz, J. P. - Department of History, Cornell University, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Beale, Howard K., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bemis, S. F., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bolton, H. E., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Cottrell, E. A., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Birch, C. A. - F. S. Crofts and Co., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, C-H, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Dulles, John Foster, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Earle, Edward Mead, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Gros, Robert R., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, H-M, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Herrick, Frances H., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Hunter, Charles H., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Koontz, L. K., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Lattimore, Owen, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Leebrick, K. C. - President, Kent State University, Ohio, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, M-P, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Mitchell, Thornton, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Martin, C. E., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Martin, P. A., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Merk, Frederick - Department of History, Harvard University, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Nettels, Curtis, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, R-T, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Swain, Robert E., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Savelle, Max, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Spaulding, E. Wilder, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Savage, Carlton, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Tansill, Charles C., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Tinsley, William, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, T-Z, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Van Alstyne, R. W., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Wilber, Allen S. - F. S. Crofts and Co., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, A-C, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Beale, Howard K., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Bemis, S. F., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Crofts, F. S., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Birch, C. A., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, C-D, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Cottrell, E. A., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Dittus, C. W. - John Hopkins Press, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, D-F, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Dittus, C. W., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Earle, Edward M., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, F-K, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Fox, Dixon Ryan, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Gros, Robert R., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Hunter, C. H., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Klingberg, Frank J. - Department of History, UCLA, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, M-R, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Mitchell, Thornton, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Meyerhoff, Richard A. - Lieutenant, Air Corps Basic Flying School, Moffett Field, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Oppenheimer, Monroe - Board of Economic Warfare, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, L-M, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Lonn, Ella - Department of History, Goucher College, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Lanning, John Tate - Department of History, Duke University, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Lutz, Ralph H., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Lattimore, Owen, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, M-R, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Mitchell, Thornton, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Meyerhoff, Richard A. - Lieutenant, Air Corps Basic Flying School, Moffett Field, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Oppenheimer, Monroe - Board of Economic Warfare, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, R-V, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Ragatz, L. J., 1942 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Savelle, Max, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Savage, Carlton, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Spaulding, E. Wilder, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 29)